# Lorenzo Aceti

Full-Stack Software Engineer | React, TypeScript, Next.js, Node.js, Python, Django +55 21 965400438 | <a href="mailto:lorenzo.acetii@gmail.com">lorenzo.acetii@gmail.com</a> | <a href="mailto:portfolio">portfolio</a> | <a href="mailto:linkedin">linkedin</a> | <a href="mailto:github">github</a>

#### **ABOUT ME**

I have 3 years of experience as a full-stack developer, focusing on frontend, standing out in all the positions I've been in, reaching a high level of seniority and understanding of processes. I'm experienced in large projects, working interdisciplinary between design and software development sectors, as well as looking for product improvement solutions, such as refactorings and project structuring. I use advanced English for internal communication and with multinational clients.

# **MAIN ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Develop the interface, front-end and back-end of an equipment prediction and monitoring application, for a project that won the Petrobras Connections for Innovation program and which was presented with great success at the Web Summit 2024.
- Recreate a very large hybrid PVT modeling application, created for chemical engineers from the largest company in Brazil. I was actively involved in prototyping, redesigning and reimagining the product, in addition to implementing new technologies such as Next.js and TypeScript.
- Develop an application that helps data and computer scientists to instrument scripts for the Df-Analyzer tool, which is used to capture provenance in dataflow of scientific applications. It is being used by PhDs and PhD's students in the area and the project was invited to be published at a conference.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Full-Stack Software Engineer | HybridAI jan 2024 - present

HybridAI is a startup "spin-off" from my last company, where I was allocated a higher position, with the responsibility of refactoring, creating and improving applications and supervising projects.

- Developed the interface, front-end and back-end of an equipment prediction and monitoring application, for a project that won the Petrobras Connections for Innovation program and which was presented with great success at the Web Summit 2024.
- Recreated a very large hybrid PVT modeling application, created for chemical engineers from the largest company in Brazil, actively working on prototyping, redesigning and reimagining the product, in addition to implementing new technologies such as Next.js and TypeScript.
- Refactoring of three large projects, implementing Next.js, Typescript, and other technologies most used in the web development environment
- Created four new interfaces for the company's ongoing projects, thinking about user experience and visual identity

**Tech Stack and skills:** React, Next.JS, Typescript, Node.js, TailwindCSS, React Query, React Hook Form, Zod, Zustand, Django, Django REST Framework, Figma, Photoshop

Full-Stack Developer | ISDB FlowTech

### aug 2021 - dec 2023

Through the development of intelligent applications, ISDB FlowTech provides technical consulting solutions for the main Oil and Gas players in Brazil and abroad. This is where I started my professionalization process, where I learned important lessons in project management and the development of large-scale projects. I managed to stand out for my proactivity, accurate deliveries and high quality in software development.

- Migrated a large-scale project for one of the biggest companies in Brazil, refactoring the frontend stack from React + Javascript to Next.js 13 and Typescript. I've also created a new UI and developed the whole application from scratch.
- Started the frontend and backend development of a large-scale project for a big company, using React and TailwindCSS, libraries never used before by the team and that I myself suggested the implementation (in addition to Django in the backend).
- I presented solutions for the implementation of new technologies that would bring significant impacts on the performance and security of the company's applications.
- Developed advanced authentication systems, with JWT and email confirmations.

**Tech Stack and skills:** React, Next.JS, Typescript, TailwindCSS, React Query, React Hook Form, Zod, Zustand, Django, Django REST Framework, Styled Components, Plotly, PostgreSQL, Postman, Figma, Photoshop

## **SKILLS**

- React Js (hooks, state management, accessibility and performance)
- Tailwind CSS & CSS in Js (styled components, shadcn/ui)
- Saas (software as a service)
- Next Js (SSR, SSG, SEO)
- React router
- Django (MVC, Rest Framework)
- Node Js (streams, server)
- Javascript & TypeScript
- Git (versioning control)
- APIs Rest

- Agile teams experience
- Experience with design systems (figma & adobe products)
- Npm package managing
- Performance optimization
- React hook form and zod (advanced forms and validations)
- React query and zustand (advanced state management)
- Prisma ORM (db & sql)

#### **EDUCATION**

Federal Fluminense University
Information Systems (Bachelor's degree)

2019 - 2023

## **RELEVANT CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES**

New Class - Extensive CG (Adobe and Autodesk Authorized Training Center)
 RedZero Web Design, 2011-2014.

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English advanced
- Portuguese native